Noah Virjee

179 Cassandra Blvd., Toronto, ON | blucardin@gmail.com | (647) 540-6624 | Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github

Objective

I am a personable and motivated professional with a strong record in communication, problem-solving, and event coordination. I seek a customer service role where I can leverage my skills to effectively resolve issues, and provide a positive, supportive experience.

Key Skills

Programming Languages: Python, Java, JavaScript, C

Web Technologies: Flask, WebSockets, WebRTC, HTML,

CSS

Tools and Platforms: GitHub, VSCode, PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook, Google Cloud Platform

Databases: SQL, Redis

Word Processing: MS Office and Google Docs

Communication: Active listening, clear verbal and written communication, empathy

Problem-Solving: Conflict resolution, adaptability, and quick decision-making

Customer Relations: Strong interpersonal skills,

patience, and professionalism

Organizational: Event coordination, time management,

multitasking

Experience

Junior Full Stack Developer, Employment Readiness Scale Inc.

July 2022 – February 2023

- Developed a web application providing agencies with dynamic, user-friendly dashboards that display statistical insights from student assessments.
- Wrote API calls to access the data and aggregated and displayed the statistics with Python, Flask, HTML, and JavaScript.
- Sole developer for the project, reporting directly to the lead developer.
- Consuleted with end users to gather requirements and feedback, ensuring the application met their needs.

Event Organizer, Recess Hacks

December 2021 - December 2022

- Coordinated a hackathon for over 100 participants, ensuring smooth operations and high attendee satisfaction.
- Managed clear communication with participants, vendors, and team members, resolving issues promptly.
- Organized event logistics including scheduling, opening/closing ceremonies, and workshop facilitation.

Education

Ursula Franklin Academy, Toronto, Ontario

September 2020 – June 2024

- Graduated with honors: School Valedictorian.
- Leadership and Extracurriculars:
 - Model UN: Served as head delegate/team lead, honing negotiation and public speaking skills.
 - DECA: Competed in Marketing Communications, achieving top regional placement.
 - PALS: Facilitated transitions for new students and organized school events.
 - Peer Tutoring: Tutored students in math, CS, and sciences, emphasizing clear communication and support.

Projects

Christmas Lights Version 2

- Developed a system to play videos on addressable Christmas tree lights by determining light positions and mapping video frames accordingly.
- Utilized a Raspberry Pi for hardware control and Python for software development.

Prom Seating Arrangement

- Created an algorithm to optimize prom seating arrangements based on social network analysis and community detection
- Applied graph theory and modularity concepts to partition attendees into optimal groups.

Quicker Picker Upper

- Created a 3d printed dual-axis robotic arm for garbage collection.
- Won 2nd place at MakeUofT hackathon.

Certifications and Achievements

- CS50x Certificate: Completed Harvard's online course on Computer Science.
- CS50p Certificate: Completed Harvard's online course on Python Programming.
- CS50AI Certificate: Completed Harvard's online course on Artificial Intelligence.

References available upon request.